

### CONTACT ME AT

• London, SE5 0BB

eokuchukwu95@gmail.com

https://blissful-volhardcef363.netlify.app/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/e mmanuel-okuchukwu-677011b4/

## SKILLS SUMMARY

React.js

HTML5, CSS3 and SCSS

Javascript

Bootstrap 4

Styled-Components

Lucidchart

C#

PHP

MYSQL

Microsoft office 365

Good team player

Quick Learner

Excellent Written and Verbal Communication

# **EMMANUEL OKUCHUKWU**

# FRONTEND DEVELOPER

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I'm an IT Professional with a keen interest in Computer Programming and Web Development. I have experience with JavaScript, I use react.js for client-side and I am currently learning node.js for server side. I have some knowledge on PHP and java. My interests however lie on frontend development using react.js, html, CSS, scss and styled-components. I also have some experience using wireframe design tools like Lucid Chart, draw.io and Axure.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## Intern Web developer

Greenwich Bright G-Wizards | Dec 2017 - Sept 2018

- Initial assessment of the website to understand current problems.
- Led on-going maintenance of the web site using C#, ASP.NET.
- Designed the website user interface using CSS and HTML.

#### Trainee Database administrator

Light House | Sept 2017 - Dec 2017

- I was involved in the planning and development of the database, as well as in troubleshooting any issues on behalf of the users.
- On-going DBA duties, including maintenance, data entry & data querying.
- Database administration including installation,
- test, start-up, shutdown, administration and housekeeping.

#### **PROJECTS**

## Student Web App

https://github.com/EmmanuelOkuchukwu/student-appproject

 The student web app was a group peer assessment application designed and implemented using php,
MySQL, html and CSS. The aim of this project was to create a webapplication that could help students record the performance of the other students in their group and to also help the lecturer record the performance of all the groups in his/her class.



#### CONTACT ME AT

- London, SE5 0BB
- eokuchukwu95@gmail.com
- https://blissful-volhardcef363.netlify.app/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/e mmanuel-okuchukwu-677011b4/

## Admin Dashboard

This project is a small admin panel with crud capabilities and basic authentication with jwt that allows users to login. The front-end is react.js and backend is json server. Other additional tools used for this project was simple-reactvalidator for the error handling in the front-end and reactalert for the alert messages.

## PatientComms Management System

https://github.com/EmmanuelOkuchukwu/pms-web-ui PCMS is a web application designed and built for the purposes of online communication between a patient and their doctor. This new system will encourage patients to be in constant communication with their clinical practitioner when they do not come in to visit their doctors.

#### **EDUCATIONAL HISTORY**

# University of Greenwich

MSc Computing and Information Systems | 2019 - 2020

- Core Modules: Software Tools and Techniques (Java), User Centered Web Engineering (PHP and MySQL) and MSc Project (React and Java).
- Grade: Merit

## University of Greenwich

BSc Computing | 2014 - 2017

- Core Modules: Computer programming (Java), Information Analysis (MySQL Workbench), Application and Web Development
- Grade: 2:2

#### HOBBIES AND PERSONAL INTERESTS

I built a windows 10 PC.

I enjoy reading articles on technology and software engineering.

I enjoy developing web applications in my free time.

I enjoy playing Table tennis.